<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
      <title>Homeostasis Preservation</title>
      <link>https://hp.hinton.link</link>
      <description>Last 10 notes on Homeostasis Preservation</description>
      <generator>Quartz -- quartz.jzhao.xyz</generator>
      <item>
    <title>Homepage</title>
    <link>https://hp.hinton.link/</link>
    <guid>https://hp.hinton.link/</guid>
    <description>What is this site? This site contains the full content of every Quora post from Dewey Gaedcke referencing the concept of “homeostasis preservation” as a fundamental explanatory ...</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 19:36:29 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Would you pursue the truth even if it would result in everyone turning against you?</title>
    <link>https://hp.hinton.link/Would-you-pursue-the-truth-even-if-it-would-result-in-everyone-turning-against-you</link>
    <guid>https://hp.hinton.link/Would-you-pursue-the-truth-even-if-it-would-result-in-everyone-turning-against-you</guid>
    <description>Have you not studied my Quora feed?? I’m regularly attacked and criticized for the things I write. Things I believe are true and easily defensible … And you can tell they are likely true, because the attacks involve ad-hominem reasoning, instead of arguments based on merit or evidence.</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 19:36:29 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Would you feel disrespected if your husband or boyfriend stared at another woman&#039;s butt right in front of you?</title>
    <link>https://hp.hinton.link/Would-you-feel-disrespected-if-your-husband-or-boyfriend-stared-at-another-womans-butt-right-in-front-of-you</link>
    <guid>https://hp.hinton.link/Would-you-feel-disrespected-if-your-husband-or-boyfriend-stared-at-another-womans-butt-right-in-front-of-you</guid>
    <description>Some would &amp; some would not. The “would not”s are most likely a bit more psychologically grounded and happy in life. Here’s the deal — dopamine/testosterone/adrenaline feel good; humans like to feel good; getting a sexual arousal produces these hormones; humans often move toward feeling good unconsciously &amp; automatically; in fact the neuron’s that mediate this behavior are much faster (more automatic) than those that mediate conscious &amp; willful acts.</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 19:36:29 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Will holistic and eastern approaches to psychology and healing ever be widely accepted in the west? What would it take for its acceptance?</title>
    <link>https://hp.hinton.link/Will-holistic-and-eastern-approaches-to-psychology-and-healing-ever-be-widely-accepted-in-the-west-What-would-it-take-for-its-acceptance</link>
    <guid>https://hp.hinton.link/Will-holistic-and-eastern-approaches-to-psychology-and-healing-ever-be-widely-accepted-in-the-west-What-would-it-take-for-its-acceptance</guid>
    <description>Another respondent below, Red Lawhern, made some really good points and I commented on his post. The ensuing discussion created some useful content that I didn’t want lost down in the comments.</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 19:36:29 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Why won’t my therapist validate my racial trauma? Would her not being black have anything to do with it? Would it be training?</title>
    <link>https://hp.hinton.link/Why-wont-my-therapist-validate-my-racial-trauma-Would-her-not-being-black-have-anything-to-do-with-it-Would-it-be-training</link>
    <guid>https://hp.hinton.link/Why-wont-my-therapist-validate-my-racial-trauma-Would-her-not-being-black-have-anything-to-do-with-it-Would-it-be-training</guid>
    <description>I don’t know … perhaps you could get trained as a therapist so you have the experience and professional credentials to be certain of exactly what is best for you ...</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 19:36:29 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Why will no one admit that therapy doesn&#039;t work for some people?</title>
    <link>https://hp.hinton.link/Why-will-no-one-admit-that-therapy-doesnt-work-for-some-people</link>
    <guid>https://hp.hinton.link/Why-will-no-one-admit-that-therapy-doesnt-work-for-some-people</guid>
    <description>It seems to me that both your language and your analysis are not yet very precise. There are HUNDREDS of types of therapy … how many have you tried? And for how long?? Lets start with a few WELL UNDERSTOOD and VALIDATED FACTS Emotional and psychological suffering derives largely from repetitive loops or patterns (aka thoughts, attitudes, stories, viewpoints, emotions) in the human nervous system We do know how to change and slowly reorganize the nervous system … specifically, through practice and repetition Given those two facts above, it’s a total non-starter for laymen (people not trained in the science and methods) to make the blanket claim that “therapy doesn’t work” Thats like saying “lifting weights does not make my muscles more dense” … Sorry, thats wrong!! You may not NOTICE the change, but we actually do know how muscles work, and so this overly simplistic claim is just mistaken BUT, it is true that there are 100’s of models or modes of therapy … many different patterns for changing and retraining the nervous system And so it CAN BE REASONABLE to theorize that “therapeutic technique ABC may not help much for emotional pattern XYZ” Yes, you can make THAT CLAIM without totally breaching logic and sanity, but it’s very risky to do so.</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 19:36:29 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Why is it that when people get cheated on in a relationship, they most likely blame the third person?</title>
    <link>https://hp.hinton.link/Why-is-it-that-when-people-get-cheated-on-in-a-relationship-they-most-likely-blame-the-third-person</link>
    <guid>https://hp.hinton.link/Why-is-it-that-when-people-get-cheated-on-in-a-relationship-they-most-likely-blame-the-third-person</guid>
    <description>Our brains are all running an automatic “program” called “homeostasis preservation”. This means that we have deep unconscious fears for things changing too suddenly or too radically.</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 19:36:29 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Why is there a big emergence of anti-science people?</title>
    <link>https://hp.hinton.link/Why-is-there-a-big-emergence-of-anti-science-people</link>
    <guid>https://hp.hinton.link/Why-is-there-a-big-emergence-of-anti-science-people</guid>
    <description>The answer to this question is virtually identical to the question about the rise of Populism around the world….they have the same root cause. Human brains are pattern recognition machines….we do it really well.</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 19:36:29 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Why is it so hard to find a therapist?</title>
    <link>https://hp.hinton.link/Why-is-it-so-hard-to-find-a-therapist</link>
    <guid>https://hp.hinton.link/Why-is-it-so-hard-to-find-a-therapist</guid>
    <description>Two main reasons: there are few really high quality therapists in existence (see a book called Focusing by Gendlin if you want more info here) all humans posses an [unconscious stability ...</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 19:36:29 GMT</pubDate>
  </item><item>
    <title>Why don&#039;t therapists &quot;realize&quot; that clearing trauma isn&#039;t enough and you need to actually help people habitualize taking action, (e.g. in a situation where you can&#039;t get away from the emotional abuse because you and your child will end up homeless)?</title>
    <link>https://hp.hinton.link/Why-dont-therapists-realize-that-clearing-trauma-isnt-enough-and-you-need-to-actually-help-people-habitualize-taking-action-eg-in-a-situation-where-you-cant-get-away-from-the-emotional-abuse--04f20962</link>
    <guid>https://hp.hinton.link/Why-dont-therapists-realize-that-clearing-trauma-isnt-enough-and-you-need-to-actually-help-people-habitualize-taking-action-eg-in-a-situation-where-you-cant-get-away-from-the-emotional-abuse--04f20962</guid>
    <description>I’m fairly certain that most (even incompetent) therapists are aware that action-oriented, new behaviors are needed. I’d be surprised if many were deluded or missing-in-action on this point.</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 19:36:29 GMT</pubDate>
  </item>
    </channel>
  </rss>